(开菊兽[日语]: 巨型野兽)
(贼鸥[德语]: 猎人)
在我还是孩子的时候
When I was a kid,
每当感觉到渺小和孤单
whenever I'd feel small or lonely,
我都会抬头看着星星
I'd look up at the stars.
幻想那里存在着生命
Wondered if there was life up there.
后来我才知道我看错了方向
Turns out I was looking in the wrong direction.
原来外星生命是从太平洋底闯入到我们的世界来的
When alien life entered our world...
他们从两个板块缝隙
it was from deep beneath the pacific ocean.
从平行宇宙的入口闯入
A fissure between two tectonic plates.
我们管那里叫
A portal between dimensions.
缺口
The breach.
我15岁的时候 第一只怪兽在旧金山登陆
I was fifteen when the first kaiju made land in San Francisco.
那个时候 坦克 战斗机 导弹
By the time tanks, jets and missiles took it down...
在方圆35公里狂轰滥炸了6天 三座城市毁于一旦
six days and 35 Miles later, three cities were destroyed.
数以万计的生命在攻击中丧生
Tens of thousands of lives were lost.
我们为死者建立了公墓 纪念这场仍在继续的
We mourned our dead, memorialized the attack,
乱世之伤
and moved on.
然而 仅仅六个月之后
And then, only six months later,
第二波攻击发生在马尼拉
the second attack hit manila.
怪兽的酸性血液
Female newscaster: The acid factor of the kaiju blood...
引发了一种特殊中毒现象 怪兽氓蓝
creates a toxic phenomenon named kaiju blue.
第三波攻击发生在卡波角
And then the third one hit cabo.
之后是第四波
And then the fourth.
渐渐我们明白了 攻击是不会停止的
And then we learned this was not gonna stop.
这些仅仅是开始而已
This was just the beginning.
我们需要一种新型武器
We needed a new weapon.
世界各国联手调动所有资源
The world came together, pooling its resources...
为了打败共同的敌人
and throwing aside old rivalries...
摈弃前嫌 携手迎战
for the sake of the greater good.
为了对抗怪兽 我们需要创造自己的怪兽
To fight monsters, we created monsters of our own.
贼鸥计划应运而生
The jaeger program was born.
起初计划屡试屡败
There were setbacks at first.
单个驾驶员根本无法负担
The neural load to interface with a jaeger...
机甲战士的意识传感系统
proved too much for a single pilot.
于是便开始采用双驾驶员系统
A two-pilot system was implemented.
一个控制左半脑 一个控制右半脑
Left-hemisphere, right-hemisphere pilot control.
我们开始获胜了
We started winning.
机甲战士把怪兽打得落花流水
Jaegers stopping kaijus everywhere.
出色的驾驶员打造出最强悍的机甲战士
But the jaegers were only as good as their pilots.
他们像摇滚明星一样到处作秀
So jaeger pilots turned into rock stars.
危机变成了宣传话题
Danger turned into propaganda.
怪兽变成了儿童玩偶
Kaijus into toys.
我们最擅长的事就是
We got really good at it.
胜利
Winning.
终于
Then...
一切都改变了
Then it all changed.
危险流浪者向08号塔台 A-42级报告
Gipsy danger, report to bay 08, level a-42.
怪兽 代号刀锋头 第三代 8700吨
Kaiju. Code name: Knifehead. Category 3.
杨希 快醒醒 缺口有动静了
Yo, yancy, wake up! Movement in the breach.
快点 给我们派活了
Hey, come on! We're being deployed.
好了 早上好
Great. Good morning.
早上好
Mornin'.
第三代怪兽 迄今最大的
Kaiju's a category 3, biggest one yet.
它的代号是 刀锋头
Code name: Knifehead.
几点了
What time is it?
- 两点 - 快 快 快 快点
- 2:00. - Go, go, go! Move it!
- 早上 - 没错
- A.M.? - Yep.
感觉怎么样
What do you say?
马上要第五只了
Fifth notch on the belt?
快点 贝克特兄弟 时间到了
Come on, beckets. Time for the drop.
- 嗨 傻小子 - 怎么
- Hey, kid. - Yeah?
别瞎得瑟
Don't get cocky.
很多年前
Years before,
我绝不会相信哥哥杨希和我会成为英雄
you wouldn't have picked my brother yancy and I for heroes.
死也不会
No chance.
是 长官
Good morning, sir.
好 让我们打他个片甲不留
All right, let's suit up and kick some ass!
我们天生就不是明星的料
We were never star athletes.
天生也不是拔尖的好学生
Never at the head of the class.
可在战斗中我们却是常胜将军
But we could hold our own in a fight.
因为我们兄弟俩有一项特长
And it turned out we had a unique skill:
配合完美的通感
We were drift compatible.
能量缓冲完毕
All right.
穿戴就绪 准备就位
Data on helmet.
数据中转凝胶正全面传输中
Data relay gel dispersing in circuitry suit.
早上好 贝克特兄弟
Good morning, becket boys!
天童 你还好吗 哥们儿
Tendo, what's happening, my man?
昨晚上跟艾莉森的约会怎么样
How'd that date with Alison go last night, Mr. choi?
她超爱我 可是她男朋友敌视我
Oh, she loved me. Her boyfriend? Not so much.
你早晚会被狂扁一顿的
You're gonna get your ass kicked.
男人就该干男人该干的事 兄弟们
A man's gotta do what a man's gotta do, brother.
准备投放
Engage drop, Mr. choi.
准备投放中 长官
Engaging drop, sir.
潘特考斯将军到
Marshal pentecost on deck.
检查驾驶舱 准备投放
Securing the conn pod. Gettin' ready to drop.
驾驶舱门锁定确认
Conn pod door lock secure.
投放准备就绪 各就各位
Release for drop.
释放投放器
Gipsy danger ready for the big drop.
好戏上场了
Here we go. Yeah!
开打吧
Here we go!
确认结合 长官
Coupling confirmed, sir.
开启驾驶员之间的连线程序
Engage pilot-to-pilot protocol.
连线开始
Engaging now.
驾驶员之间连线程序进行中
Pilot-to-pilot connection protocol sequence.
流浪者启动 六号湾
Gipsy launch, bay 6.
准备完毕 正在校准 长官
Gipsy danger ready and aligned, sir.
我是斯达克·潘特考斯特将军
Rangers, this is marshal stacker pentecost.
准备神经元对接
Prepare for neural handshake.
15秒倒计时开始
Starting in 15 seconds.
14 13
14...13...
12 11 10
12, 11, 10...
准备好进入我大脑了吗 小子
Ready to step into my head, kid?
- 还是你来吧 - 我得尊老爱幼 对吧
- Please, after you. - Age before beauty, old man.
- 驾驶员之间连线程序进行中 - 5 4 3
- Pilot-to-pilot connection protocol sequence. - ...5, 4, 3...
- 神经元对接开始 - 2 1
- Neural handshake initiated. - ...2, 1.
通感 贼鸥计划
The drift. Jaeger tech.
起源于国防部高级研究局的战斗机驾驶员神经系统
Based on darpa jet fighter neural systems.
两个驾驶员 通过记忆实现心智结合
Two pilots, mind-melding through memories...
一起控制一部巨大的机器
with the body of a giant machine.
结合得越深
The deeper the bond...
能力越强大
The better you fight.
神经元对接信号强烈稳定
Neural handshake strong and holding.
大脑右半球校准中
Right hemisphere is calibrating.
大脑左半球校准中
Left hemisphere calibrating.
校准完毕 传送中
Proofed and transmitting.
先生们 你们的任务
Gentlemen, your orders are...
是守住神奇海岸线 明白吗
to hold the miracle mile off Anchorage. Copy?
遵命 长官
Copy that, sir.
长官 阿拉斯加湾有一艘航行的民用船
Sir, there's still a civilian vessel in the Gulf...
你们保护的是全城两百万人民的生命
gentlemen, you're protecting a city of 2 million people.
不能为了一艘小船顾此失彼
You will not risk those lives for a boat that holds 10.
明白吗
Am I clear?
明白 长官 真够冷血的
Yes, sir. Man, that's cold.
你知道我们什么意思
You know what I'm thinking.
我在你脑子里呢
I'm in your brain.
当然知道 一起钓鱼去吧
I know. Then let's go fishing.
好吧 哥哥
Here we go!
开始大展拳脚吧
Come on, bro! Put some muscle to it!
还是管好你自己吧 臭小子
Worry about yourself, kiddo!
有些时候渺小的人类根本对抗不了上帝
There are things you can't fight, acts of God.
比如现在暴风雨肆虐 你能做的就是躲避
You see a hurricane coming, you have to get out of the way.
可一旦你成为了机甲战士
But when you're in a jaeger,
你就强大到可以和暴风雨对抗
suddenly, you can fight the hurricane.
你就有了胜算
You can win.
(阿拉斯加海岸 海岸线10英里)
把笼子拉近 赶快到下面去
Get 'em tied down and go down below!
快 使劲儿
Now!
离陆地还有多远
How far to the mainland?
离安克雷奇还有7英里 船长
7 Miles off Anchorage, sir.
可我们现在连浅滩都到不了
But we won't even make it past the shallows!
不 不可能
No, we won't!
东面3英里的那个小岛呢
What about that island 3 Miles east?
天呐 两英里了 船长
No! No! It's two Miles, sir.
一英里了 船长
O-one mile, sir!
越来越近了
It's getting closer.
它到底为什么会越来越近
How the hell can it be getting closer?
怪兽
Kaiju.
赶快右满舵
Harder starboard!
赶快掉头 快点 越来越近了
I'm doing it as fast as I can!
快
Now!
天呐
Oh, God!
什么鬼东西
What the hell?
抓紧
Hang on!
船只安全
Ship secure.
- 校准扭矩 - 校准
- Adjust the torque! - I'm on it.
扭矩锁定
Torque locked.
- 抓住它了 快 - 开炮
- Get him. Come on. - Shoot him.
炮弹上膛
I'm on it! I'm on it!
放电阅读 长官
Discharge reading, sir.
等离子榴弹炮在距海岸线七英里的浅陆架爆炸
Plasma Cannon in the shallow shelves 7 Miles off the coastal line.
流浪者 发生了什么事
Gipsy, what the hell is going on?
任务完成 长官 发射两次
Job's done, sir. Lit it up twice.
干掉了第五个敌人
Bagged our fifth kill.
可是你们违反了我的直接指令
You disobeyed a direct order!
向您汇报 长官
Respectfully, sir,
我们不但拦截了怪兽 还拯救了船上人的性命
we intercepted a kaiju and saved everyone on that boat.
马上回到你们的位置
Get back to your post, now!
是 长官
Yes, sir.
怪兽的生命迹象在增强
Kaiju signature rising!
传感器检查
Sensor checks.
那鬼东西还活着 流浪者
That thing's still alive, sir. Gipsy!
我们还是可以读到信号
We're still getting a signature!
那怪兽还活着
That kaiju is still alive!
带着渔船赶快离开那里
Grab the boat and get out of there.
听到了吗
You copy?
带着渔船赶快离开现场
Grab the boat and get out of there now!
你控制它 罗利 我再给它一击
Take it, Raleigh! I got this!
我被击中了
Loccent, we're hit!
左臂失去动力 长官
Left arm's gone cold, sir.
外壳 外壳被刺穿了
The hull! It went through the hull!
罗利听我说 你需要…
Raleigh, listen to me! You need...
不 不
no! No!
蓄力中
Loading.
第二次发射破坏了所有通讯
Second discharge fried all the comms, sir.
完全没有信号
I'm not getting any signals.
压力下降
Pressure dropping!
失去压力 重复 失去压力
No pressure! Repeat: No pressure!
没有信号 长官
No signatures, sir.
现在怎么办 长官
What do we do now, sir?
现在你要紧盯着这个测量仪
Now, I want you to keep your eye on that gauge there.
这会儿你该知道我在找什么了吧
Now, you know what I'd like to find?
我在找一艘船
I'd like to find a whole ship.
我来这儿就是为了它
That's what I'd like to find.
等等 等等
Wait, wait!
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
等等 就在这儿 就在这儿
Wait! Right there, right there!
快挖
Dig!
这是什么
Hey, what is it?
像是一个旧玩具
It's just an old toy.
我们从来都挖不到宝贝
We never find anything good.
快听
Listen.
天呐
Jeez!
我的天呐
Oh, my God.
你待在这儿
Stay here!
先生
Mister?
我能帮你吗
Can I help?
杨希
Yancy.
快点 快去找救援
Run! Get help, fast!
没事了 撑住 先生
It's gonna be all right.
《环太平洋》
怪兽找到了我们的弱点
The kaiju are learning our defenses.
它们已经适应了 进化了
They're adapting. Evolving.
机甲战士被毁的速度高于生产速度
And we're losing jaegers faster than we can build them.
利马城
Lima.
西雅图
Seattle.
海参崴
Vladivostok.
第四代怪兽正通过缺口长驱直入
Category 4 kaijus are now coming through the breach.
我相信你也看得出来 将军
I think even you can see, marshal,
这战略计划已经不管用了
this is no longer a sound strategy.
随着攻击次数和强度不断增加
The frequency of the attacks has increased.
贼鸥机甲战士现在已经不再是
The jaegers are not the most viable...
最有力的钢铁防线了
line of defense anymore.
这我完全知道
I am aware.
每一个机甲战士倒下就意味着更多的特种兵牺牲
Those are my rangers that die every time a jaeger falls,
这就是我为什么
which is why I'm asking you for one last chance...
打断你一下 将军
Excuse me, marshal. Excuse me!
- 恳求你们 动用我们所有的力量拼死一搏 - 打断你一下
- ...one final assault with everything we've got. - Listen to me.
贼鸥计划已经名存实亡了 将军
The jaeger program is dead, marshal.
另一方面
On the other hand,
海岸围墙筑造倒是值得考虑的计划
the coastal wall program is a promising option.
全世界都会铭记
The world appreciates...
你和你的部队所做的贡献
all that you and your men have done,
我们会让你
but it's over. We will authorize you...
带着剩下的机甲战士退居最后的战场
to take all remaining jaegers to the last battle station:
香港
Hong Kong.
接下来的八个月我们还会继续资助你
We're prepared to fund you for the next eight months...
直到海岸围墙筑造完毕
while the coastal wall is completed.
以后我们不会再向你提供资金了
After that, you will receive no further support.
这是最终结果 将军
You have your answer, marshal.
最终结果
So that's it?
结束了
It's over?
西装革履 人模人样
Suits and ties, flashy smiles.
他们就是这种人
That's all they are, stacker.
我们自己干
We don't need 'em.
("生命之墙" 阿拉斯加州 锡特卡)
(阿拉斯加-加利福尼亚 怪兽防御墙工程)
定量供应卡 过来
Ration cards, guys!
过来 过来
Come on, come on!
都过来
Let's go!
我有一个好消息和一个坏消息 伙计们
Now, I got good news and I got bad news, fellas.
你们想先听哪个
Which one you wanna hear first?
坏消息
Bad news!
Bad news:
坏消息是三个人死了 他们昨天在墙头上工作
Three guys died yesterday working the top of the wall.
好消息是什么
What's the good news?
好消息是这儿三个空缺职位
The good news is, I got three new job openings.
顶昨天死的弟兄
Top of the wall.
好了 想得到这个工作的人 想吃饱饭的人
Okay, who wants to work? Who wants to eat?
来吧
Come on!
我在悉尼为大家报道 今天早些时候
I am here in Sydney, where earlier today,
怪兽发起了新一轮的攻势
yet another kaiju attack took place.
体型巨大的第四代怪兽
The kaiju, an enormous category 4,
花了不到一小时便攻陷了海岸围墙
broke through the coastal wall in less than an hour.
这一突袭迅速有力得证明了
The wall of life had been deemed unbreachable...
生命之墙的形同虚设
by its builders.
我们到底是在建造什么玩意儿
Why the hell are we even buildin' this thing?
怪兽通过悉尼湾入侵城市
The creature entered the city through Sydney cove.
那东西
That...that thing...
- 几乎没使劲就把墙打烂了 - 讽刺的是
- went through the wall like it was nothing. - Ironically, it was...
最近宣布退役的机甲战士尤里卡突袭者
the recently decommissioned jaeger, striker Eureka,
驾驶员汉森父子
piloted by herc and Chuck Hansen,
最终打败了入侵的怪兽
that finally took the beast down.
他们因为那些
Look, they decommissioned...
无能的机甲战士 就想叫停贼鸥计划
the jaeger program because of mediocre pilots.
太欠考虑
It's that simple.
这是突袭者干掉的第十个怪兽
That's striker Eureka's tenth kill to date.
刷新了纪录
It's a new record.
现在这里的情况这么糟 你还要坚持去香港吗
And you're still going to Hong Kong, even at a time like this?
俗话说军令如山 我不能违抗指令
Well, orders are orders. What else am I supposed to do?
来吧 伙计
Come on, mate.
我们刚刚采访的是查克·汉森
Chuck Hansen, one of the pilots of striker Eureka,
正是战胜怪兽的尤里卡突袭者的驾驶员之一
the jaeger that took down the kaiju.
贝克特先生
Mr. becket.
将军 别来无恙
Marshal. Looking sharp.
好久不见
Long time.
五年零四个月了
Five years, four months.
能聊几句吗
Can I have a word?
所有三区的焊工请注意
Attention, all zone three welders.
到我办公室来说吧
Step into my office, marshal.
找你可没少花功夫
Took me a while to find you.
安克雷奇市 谢尔顿市 诺姆省
Anchorage, Sheldon point, nome...
我干的活就是得跟着这堵墙走
yeah, a man in my position travels with the wall,
混口饭吃而已
chasing shifts to make a livin'.
找我什么事
What do you want?
我花了六个月时间
I've spent the last six months...
去修复激活所有的机甲战士
activating everything I can get my hands on.
有一台老机器 编号第三
There's an old jaeger, a mark 3.
你应该知道 它需要一个驾驶员
You may know it. It needs a pilot.
我想你的首选不是我吧
I'm guessing I wasn't your first choice.
你就是我的首选
You amy first choice.
所有驾驶过三号的驾驶员都死了
All the other mark 3 pilots are dead.
其实
Look...
我已经无法再接受别人进入我大脑了
I can't have anyone else in my head again.
我死了
I'm done.
在我哥哥死的时候 和他链接的我也死了
I was still connected to my brother when he died.
对不起 我这辈子不想再经历了
I can't go through that again, man, I'm sorry.
你听过这个说法吗 贝克特先生
Haven't you heard, Mr. becket?
世界末日就要来了
The world is coming to an end.
到那个时候你想死在哪儿
So where would you rather die? !
这儿 还是机甲里
Here, or in a jaeger? !
(香港港湾 18点)
(碎片圆顶-贼鸥基地)
贝克特先生 这是森麻子小姐
Mr. becket, this is mako mori.
我们这儿最聪明的一个
One of our brightest.
她专门负责三号机甲的修复工作
Also in charge of the mark 3 restoration program.
她亲自为你挑选了配合你的候选人
She personally handpicked your copilot candidates.
他跟我想象的不同
嗨
Hey.
更好还是更糟
我很抱歉贝克特先生 我听说过很多关于你的事
稍息
At ease.
我先带你参观一下
We will tour the facility first...
然后麻子小姐带你去看你的机甲战士
and then miss mori will show you to your jaeger, Mr. becket.
- 等我们一下 - 别关门
- Wait for us, please! - Hold the door, please!
谢谢 谢谢
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
别靠近 怪兽样本是极其罕见的
Stay back! Kaiju specimens are extremely rare,
所以只能看不能摸
so look but don't touch, please.
贝克特先生 这是我们的研究小组
Mr. becket, this is our research team.
戈特利布博士和葛斯勒博士
Dr. gottlieb and Dr. geiszler.
别 叫我纽顿
Oh, no, call me newt.
只有我妈会叫我博士
Only my mother calls me doctor.
赫尔曼 这些都是人类 打个招呼吧
Hermann, these are human beings. Why don't you say hello?
我跟你说过 别在别人面前直呼我名字
I have asked you not to refer to me by my first name around others.
我是个有十年辉煌成就的优秀博士
I am a doctor with over 10 years decorated experience...
- 噢 不 对 - 十年辉煌成就的优秀博士
- Oh, no, yes. I have ten... - 10 years of experience, man.
真是的
I'm very sorry.
噢 拜托
Oh, please.
纹的是雅玛拉奇
Who is that, yamarashi?
哦 你说这只小怪兽 对 你挺有眼力
Oh, this little kaiju? Yeah, you got a good eye.
我和我哥哥在2017年干掉它的
My brother and I took him down in 2017.
它可是第三代怪兽里最大个的
You know he was one of the biggest category 3s ever?
你知道它重达2500吨吗
He was 2, 500 tons of awesome.
你心里是不是觉得很落伍
Or awful. You know, whatever you wanna call it.
你千万别见怪
Yes, please excuse him.
他是个怪兽粉丝 他超爱怪兽
He's a kaiju groupie. He loves...
闭嘴 赫尔曼 我不爱它们好不好
shut up, hermann, I don't love them, okay?
我研究它们
I study them.
我和普通人想法不同
And unlike most people,
我希望哪天能看看活的
I wanna see one alive and up close one day.
相信我 你会后悔的
Trust me, you don't want to.
这就是你所谓的研究部门
So that's your research division?
今非昔比了
Things have changed.
我们不再是军队了 贝克特先生
We're not an army anymore, Mr. becket.
我们现在是地下组织
We're the resistance.
欢迎加入碎片圆顶
Welcome to the shatterdome.
战事钟
War clock.
每次怪兽进攻我们都会重置时间
We reset it after every kaiju attack.
以此警醒大家
Keeps everyone focused.
现在进攻次数越来越频繁
The frequency of attacks is accelerating.
下次重置在什么时候
How long till the next reset?
一周后 如果够幸运的话
A week, if we're lucky.
我的专家们认为 用不了一周
My experts believe there'll be a kaiju attack...
就会有一次怪兽进攻
even before that.
这个基地的五个港湾
This complex used to lodge 30 jaegers...
曾经容得下三十个机甲战士
in five bays just like this one.
现在只剩下四个了
Now we only have four jaegers left.
真不知道情况这么糟
I didn't know it was this bad.
确实很糟
It is that bad.
红色暴风 中国产
Crimson typhoon, China.
最伟大的一个
One of the greatest.
在常州组装的
Assembled in changzhou.
钛金打造纯度极高
Full titanium core, no alloys.
每条肌带由50台柴油引擎组成
Fifty diesel engines per muscle strand.
百发百中的杀手
Deadly, precise fighter.
她由唐氏兄弟驾驶
She's piloted by the wei tang brothers.
他们是三胞胎
Triplets.
本地人
Local lads.
他们七次击溃了敌人 成功保卫了香港湾
They've successfully defended Hong Kong port seven times.
他们用的是雷云战术
They use the thundercloud formation.
我知道 三手臂技巧
Oh, yeah. Triple-arm technique.
非常有效
Very effective.
那家伙是T90型最后一部
That tank, last of the t-90s.
切尔诺阿尔法 第一代里一号机甲
Cherno Alpha. First generation mark 1.
目前仍在服役的最重最老的机甲战士
The heaviest and oldest jaeger in the service.
可别小看它 它是最残忍的战争机器
But make no mistake, Mr. becket, it's a brutal war machine.
这两个
And those two,
就是萨尔莎和阿历克西斯
Sasha and aleksis kaidanovksy.
是啊 我听说过
Yeah, I've heard of 'em.
负责巡逻西伯利亚海岸围墙的战士
Perimeter patrol, siberian wall.
在他们的看守下 六年没出过状况
On theiwatch it stayed unbreached for six years.
六年啊
Six years.
赫克 查克
Herc! Chuck!
先生们 欢迎来到香港
Gentlemen, welcome to Hong Kong!
等我一会儿
Wait here.
麦克斯 到这儿来
Max! Come here!
还记得我吗
Remember me?
别想讨好麻子小姐
Don't drool all over miss mori. Hi.
它每次看见美女 就哈喇子满地
Sees a pretty girl and he gets all wound up.
罗利 这是赫克
Raleigh, this is Hercules Hansen,
一起携手走过辉煌第一代机甲的老朋友
an old friend from the mark 1 glory days.
我认识你 伙计 我们一起打过仗
I know you, mate. We rode together before.
六年前 我和我哥哥
We did, sir. Six years ago. My brother and I.
- 那是三组一起出动的任务 - 对 在马尼拉
- It was a three jaeger team drop. - That's right. Manila.
你哥哥的事情我很难过
Sorry about your brother.
谢谢 长官
Thank you, sir.
赫克和他儿子查克是先遣组
Herc and his son Chuck'll be runnin' point...
驾驶突袭者
usin' striker Eureka.
是全世界速度最快的
Fastest jaeger in the world.
这是第一个 也是最后一个五代机甲
First and last of the mark 5s.
澳大利亚刚让它退役没几天后 悉尼就沦陷了
Australia decommissioned it a day before the Sydney attack.
- 幸好我们又在这儿集结了 - 没错
- Yeah, it was lucky we were still around. - Yep.
现在它是计划成败的关键
Now it's runnin' point for us.
计划成败的关键
Wait, running point on what?
你还没说让我来这儿干什么呢
You haven't told me what I'm doing here yet.
我们计划消灭缺口
We're going for the breach, Mr. becket.
我们打算捆上一个2400磅的
We're gonna strap a 2,400 pound...
热核炸弹在突袭者背上
thermonuclear warhead to striker's back.
爆炸威力等同于120万吨烈性炸药
Detonate an equivalent of 1. 2 million tons of tnt,
你和另外两个机甲战士负责掩护他们
and you and two other jaegers'll be runnin' defense for them.
我们不是转入地下了吗
Thought we were the resistance.
哪儿弄来那么多炸药
Where'd you get something that big?
看见刚才的俄国人了
See the Russians back there?
他们有办法
They can get us anything.
赫克 来一下
Herc, shall we?
很高兴你能回来
Good to have you back.
谢谢 长官
Thank you, sir.
我带你去见你的机甲战士
I'll show you to your jaeger now.
麻子小姐 等一下好吗
Miss mori, will you give me a minute?
将军
Marshal!
我们以前进攻过那个缺口
Sir, we've hit the breach before.
没成功 没有东西能攻破它
It doesn't work. Nothing goes through.
你怎么这么自信
What's changed?
我制定了个计划 需要你加入
I've got a plan. I need you ready.
就这样
That's all.
走吧 赫克
Let's go, herc!
麦克斯 给我过来
Max, come here!
17小组 听到广播后请到五层来
Crew 17, please report to the fifth floor.
〇减二
Zero minus two.
XY减二
XY minus two.
R E Q
R-e-q.
一开始
In the beginning,
怪兽进攻每次间隔24周
the kaiju attacks were spaced by 24 weeks.
然后12周 6周 然后是每次2周
Then 12, then 6, then every 2 weeks.
上一次在悉尼进攻仅隔1周
The last one in Sydney was a week.
四天内 我们可能每八小时就能看见一头怪兽
In four days, we could be seeing a kaiju every eight hours...
直到它们每四分钟就进攻一次
until they are coming every four minutes.
将军 七天内它们可能同时在两个地方发动进攻
Marshal, we should witness a double event within seven days.
戈特利布先生
Mr. gottlieb,
我将要投下2400磅的热核炸弹
I'm to drop a 2, 400 pound thermonuclear bomb.
绝不允许仅仅是可能
I need more than a prediction.
这个 还真是个问题
Well, uh, that's a problem, then...
因为对于未来的事情
because see, he actually...
他能给出的只有可能
can't give you anything more than a prediction.
别把怪兽内脏扔到我这儿
No kaiju entrails over my side of the room.
你知道我的原则
You know the rules.
每天血淋呼啦的 没完没了
Every bloody day. It's incessant.
先生 回到重点
Gents! On point.
数字是不会撒谎的
Numbers do not lie.
政治 诗歌 承诺 这些才是谎言
Politics and poetry, promises, these are lies.
数字真实可信的程度就跟上帝的手稿一样
Numbers are as close as we get to the handwriting of God.
什么
What?
你能让我说完吗
Would you give me a moment?
将会同时出现两只怪兽
There will be a double event...
之后很快就会出现三只
and then, shortly thereafter, three.
然后是四只
And then four.
然后我们完了
And then we're dead.
我明白
I get it. Alas.
是的 但还有一个好消息
This is where the good news comes.
这就是我们的宇宙
Here is our universe,
这个是它们的
and here is theirs.
而这里是被称作喉舌的地方
And this is what we call "the throat,"
是缺口和我们之间的通道
The passage between the breach and us.
我们都知道它的本质是原子能
We know that it's atomic in nature.
我的预测是 加剧的攻击频率
I predict that the increased traffic...
会强迫缺口稳固下来
will force the breach to stabilize...
保持状态
and remain open long enough...
直到让炸药通过
to get the device through...
然后摧毁这个通道
And collapse its structure.
好吧 我想我必须得插点话
Yeah, and that's where I gotta chime in...
因为说真的 我是不会进到那种地方的
because, really, I wouldn't wanna go in there...
在我什么都不能确定的情况下
with that limited amount of information.
那是你胆小如鼠
Newton, don't embarrass yourself.
听我说 就听我说几句
That's what I was tryin' to say. Just hear me out for a second.
几秒钟就够 求你了
Give me a second, please.
为什么我们把怪兽划为不同的种类
Why do we judge the kaiju on a category system?
因为这只和另一只完全不同 对吧
It's because each one is completely different from the next, right?
大家都知道 有些怪兽是尖的 有些像只鱼
You see what I'm saying? One looks like a shark and one looks like a fish...
葛斯勒博士 能不能谈重点
Dr. geiszler. Just get to the point.
对 重点是我不认为
Yes. The point is I don't think...
它们都是完全不同的
they're all completely different after all.
我选取了一些怪兽样本
These are some samples I collected, all right?
这款样本是悉尼的那只
Now, this one here was harvested in Sydney.
而这块来自马尼拉
And this was harvested in manila.
那是6年前了
6 years ago.
它们具有完全吻合的DNA
They have the same exact DNA.
无性繁殖
They're clones.
我看他的重点就是他自己 已经走火入魔了
And this is the point where he goes completely crazy.
这些怪兽身上有太多我们不能理解的东西
There's so much more to the kaiju than we understand.
只能从表面上来解释一些问题
And we've really only scratched the surface.
这是怪兽大脑的一部分
This is a piece of a kaiju's brain.
虽然不幸的是它被损坏了
Now, unfortunately, it's damaged.
而且很虚弱 但它仍然是活的
It's a little bit weak. But it's still alive.
我想我进入它的神经元
Now, I think I can tap into it...
运用将两个机甲驾驶员的
using the same technology...
神经桥接相同的技术
that allows the two jaeger pilots to share a neural bridge.
你们想想看
Now, think about that.
这样我就可以告诉你
I could tell you exactly...
准确的穿越裂缝的方法了
how to get through the breach yourselves.
你的建议是让我们和怪兽进行通感
You're suggesting that we initiate a drift with a kaiju?
不不不 不是和整只怪兽
No, no. No, no. Not like a whole kaiju, you know,
只是和它这一小部分的脑子
just a tiny piece of its brain.
这种强烈神经刺激 恐怕人类承受不了
The neural surge would be too much for the human brain.
- 说得没错 - 不是这样
- I agree. - I don't agree.
戈特利布 整理好研究数据尽快交给我
Gottlieb, I'd like your data on my desk asap.
遵命
Sir.
- 但是他的研究也太… - 谢谢你 纽顿
- No, but his is so... - thank you, newt.
先生们 这项研究会让你们大吃一惊的
Guys, now, this is the most amazing thing...
纽顿 我知道你渴望证明自己是对的
Newton, I know that you're desperate to be right...
这样也不枉费你作为怪兽粉丝的事实
so you've not wasted your life being a kaiju groupie,
但你那套空有其表
but it's not going to work.
绝对有用的 赫尔曼
It is going to work, hermann.
我还想跟你说点别的
And I'll tell you something else.
机会总给勇敢的人
Fortune favors the brave, dude.
你都听到了
You heard them.
他们绝对不会给你任何实验器材的
They won't give you the equipment...
你会小命不保
and even if they did, you'd kill yourself.
也许功成名就
Well, I'd be a rock star.
她就在那儿
There she is.
我的天呐
Oh, my God.
看看她
Look at her.
危险流浪者
Gipsy danger.
天呐 她可真漂亮
God, it's so beautiful.
看上去跟新的一样
She looks like new.
比新的更棒
Better than new.
她拥有双核心核反应器
She has a double-core nuclear reactor.
她现在是独一无二的
She's one of a kind now.
她一直都是
She always was.
喜欢你的战士吗 贝克特伙计
How do you like your ride, becket boy?
固体铁质外壳 超纯对精钢
Solid iron hull, no alloys.
每条肌带上有40个引擎机组
Forty engine blocks per muscle strands.
四肢配备超级控制
Hyper-torque driver for every limb...
全新的系统
and a new fluid synapse system.
怎么样 哥们儿
Come here.
天童
Tendo.
见到你太好了
It's good to see you, buddy.
见到你我也很开心 兄弟
It's good to see you too, brother.
就像回到了旧时光
It's just like old times.
你为什么来这儿
So what's your story?
想重振机甲战士雄风
Restoring old jaegers,
帮助我这老树开新花
showing has-beens like me around.
不会是因为这个吧
That can't be it.
你是驾驶员
You a pilot?
不 还不是
No. No yet.
但我特别想成为驾驶员
But I wanna be one, more than anything.
你的模拟器成绩是多少
What's your simulator score?
52投 51杀
51 drops, 51 kills.
噢 那很棒啊
Wow, that's amazing.
可你明天却没在候选之列
But you're not one of the candidates tomorrow?
我也不清楚
I am not.
将军自有他的道理吧
The marshal has his reasons.
是啊 他总是对的 是吗
Yeah, he always does, doesn't he?
可51次的记录 我想不出他有什么理由
But with 51 kills, I can't imagine what they could be.
希望你能喜欢我挑选的人
I hope you approve of my choices.
我是根据的你的战斗技巧和策略认真挑选的
I've studied your fighting techniques and strategy.
特别是阿拉斯加那次
Even...Alaska.
你有什么想法
And what do you think?
我觉得你不受控制
I think you're unpredictable.
你经常有偏离
You have a habit of deviating...
既定战略战术的习惯
from standard combat techniques.
你让你和你的战友陷入危机和伤害中
You take risks and injure yourself and your crew.
我不认为你是这次行动的最佳人选
I don't think you're the right man for this mission.
喔
Wow.
感谢你的诚实
Thank you for your honesty.
或许你是对的
You might be right.
可有一天你若成为驾驶员
But one day, when you're a pilot,
你亲眼看到了战场 你就得下决策
you're gonna see that in combat you make decisions.
你也必须承担得起一切的后果
And you have to live with the consequences.
这是我坚持的理念
That's what I'm trying to do.
候选人都准备好了
The candidates are ready.
选拔赛马上就要开始了 将军
We will commence the trials immediately, sir.
- 很好 - 但还有一件事
- Good. - But there is one thing.
- 我们… - 麻子 我们已经讨论过了
- We... - mako, we have talked about this.
我想不需要再讨论了
We will not be talking about it again.
嗯
Hm?
你答应过我的
You promised me.
我应该跟他一起驾驶流浪者
麻子
Mako.
复仇 就像撕开愈合的伤口
Vengeance is like an open wound.
你不能带着这样的情绪参加通感行动
You cannot take that level of emotion into the drift.
为了我的家人 我需要…
For my family, I need...
你需要更多时间
罗利
Raleigh.
跟我们坐吧
Come sit with us.
没关系 谢谢 我坐上面
Oh, I'm okay, thank you.
来吧 这桌有的是地方
Ah, come on, there's plenty of room at our table.
很久没见过面包了
I haven't seen bread in awhile.
香港
Hong Kong.
开放港口好处多 不限制配额
Beauty of an open port, no rationing.
我们有土豆 豌豆 荷兰豆 很正点的肉卷
We've got potatoes, peas, sweet beans, decent meat loaf.
把土豆递给我
Pass the potatoes.
罗利 我儿子查克 也是我的副驾驶
Raleigh, this is my son, Chuck. He's my copilot now.
你才是我的副驾驶 对吧 老爸
He's more my copilot, right, dad?
那么 你就是那个人了
So you're the guy, eh?
那个带着一副老掉牙的蒸汽机引擎
You're the guy who's gonna run defense for me...
负责掩护我的人
in that old rust bucket of yours?
- 这是计划 - 很好
- That's the plan. - Good.
雷利 你最后驾驶是什么时候
So when was the last time you jockeyed, ray?
大概五年前吧
About five years ago.
这五年你都在干什么
What have you been doin' for five years?
一定是很重要的事情了
Something pretty important, I reckon.
我在建筑工地干活
I was in construction.
喔 不赖嘛
Oh, wow, that's great.
真的是太有用了
I mean, that's really useful.
那你打仗的时候
Uh, you know, we get into a fight,
可以给我造一条逃跑之路了 雷利
you can build our way out of it, eh, ray?
我叫罗利
It's Raleigh.
无所谓
Whatever.
听着 也许你是将军的好牌
Look, you're pentecost's bright idea.
我们家老爷子好像也挺喜欢你
My old man, he seems to like you,
但像你这样的人只会拖后腿
but it's guys like you who brought down the jaeger program.
对我来说 你是个累赘 你跟不上我的速度
To me, you're dead weight. You slow me down,
我甩你就像甩一袋怪兽屎
I'm gonna drop you like a sack of kaiju shit.
回头见 罗利
I'll see you around, Raleigh.
走 麦克斯
Come, Max.
要怪就怪我吧
You can blame me for that one.
养不教父之过
I've raised him on my own.
他一直很出色
He's a smart kid, but I never knew...
出色到我不知道该拥抱他还是教训他
whether to give him a hug or a kick in the ass.
恕我直言 长官
With respect, sir...
有时候该赏罚分明
I'm pretty sure which one he needs.
(候选人选拔赛 6点)
比分是4比0
4 points to zero.
现在是4比1
4 points to 1.
比分是4比2
4 points to 2.
怎么回事
Okay, what?
你不喜欢他们
You don't like 'em?
他们不是你亲自挑选的吗
I thought you selected them personally.
什么意思
Excuse me?
每次对打结束
Every time a match ends...
你都是这副表情
you make this little gesture,
好像对他们的表现很不满意一样
like you're critical of their performance.
不是他们的表现 是你的
It's not their performance, it's yours.
你的打斗策略
Your gambit.
你不需要用这么多招数就已经可以打败他们
You could have taken all of them two moves earlier.
你这么认为
You think so?
这是事实
I know so.
那就改变比赛规则
Can we change this up?
让她来试试怎么样
How 'bout we give her a shot?
不
No.
我们要严格按照参赛名单来
We stick to the cadet list we have, ranger.
只有具有通感能力的候选人才能…
Only candidates with drift compatibility...
我就具备 将军
which I have, marshal.
麻子 这不仅仅需要神经连接
Mako, this is not only about a neural connection.
物理相容性也很需要
It's also about a physical compatibility.
有什么问题吗
What's the matter, marshal?
你不认为你的这位得意门生能打得过我
Don't think your brightest can cut it in the ring with me?
去
Go.
四招之内制胜
Four strikes marks a win.
要记住 一切要以相容为主
Remember, it's about compatibility.
这是对话 不是打架
It's a dialogue, not a fight.
不过 我不会迁就你的
But I'm not gonna dial down my moves.
好啊
Okay.
我也不会迁就你
Then neither will I.
1比0
1-0.
1比1
1-1.
2比1 集中注意力
2-1. Concentrate.
2比2
2-2.
最好小心点
Better watch it.
3比2
3-2.
麻子小姐 控制情绪
Mori-San.
够了
Enough.
我看到需要的了
I've seen what I need to see.
我也是
Me too.
她就是我的副驾驶了
She's my copilot.
这是行不通的
That's not going to work.
为什么
Why not?
因为我有权决定 先生
Because I said so, Mr. becket.
我已经做好了决定
I made my decision.
两小时后岛碎片圆顶报到
Report to the shatterdome in two hours...
到时候就知道谁是你的副驾驶了
and find out who your copilot will be.
麻子
Mako.
麻子 这到底是为什么
What was all that about?
我不是随便想想的 你能感觉到吧
I mean, I'm not crazy. You felt it, right?
我们之间存在通感
We are drift compatible.
谢谢你这么支持我
Thank you for standing up for me.
但是 我想你没办法改变他的主意
But there is nothing to talk about.
那是我的房间
That's my room.
不好意思
Excuse me.
能不能 别怕 我知道你想成为一个驾驶员
I mean, come on. I thought you wanted to be a pilot.
麻子 这是值得争取的
Mako, this is worth fighting for.
我们不需要事事听他的
We don't have to just obey him.
我并不是唯命是从的人 贝克特先生
It's not obedience, Mr. becket.
这是一种尊重
It's respect.
能不能告诉我 到底是什么问题
Would you at least tell me what his problem is?
悉尼事件后的短短几日
In the wake of the Sydney incident,
生命之墙计划被证明形同虚设
which showed the ineffective nature of the wall of life program,
公众开始质疑政府的真正动机
many are questioning the government's motives...
他们到底为什么无故中断贼鸥计划
and wondering why the jaeger program has been discontinued.
民众的大规模暴动游行
Riots have erupted along the coastlines...
在环太平洋海岸线附近多个城市爆发
of several pan pacific cities.
我们现在已经迁移了数百万灾民和物资
We have now relocated millions of civilians...
安全地带已选在离内陆约500公里的某处
and supplies 300 Miles inland to the safe zones.
安全地带 那是个富人和权贵的
Safe zones? For the rich and powerful?
我们这些普通民众呢
What about the rest of us?
快回答我们的问题
Yeah, answer the question.
我相信生命之墙
I believe the wall of life...
依旧是目前我们最大的保障
is still our best option at this time.
就此事我能说的只有这么多
And that's all I'm gonna say on the matter.
谢谢
Than...thank you.
怪兽人类通感测试第一次
Kaiju/human drift experiment, take one.
这个 大脑残片是前额叶
The, uh... the brain segment is the frontal lobe.
但是 很有可能
Um, chances are...
由于残缺严重无法实现通感
The segment's far too damaged to drift with.
再说点题外话
Unscientific aside:
赫尔曼 无论你听到这些也好
Hermann, if you're listening to this,
还是我仍然活着
well, I'm either alive...
并且证明我的实验奏效也好
and I've proven what I've just done works...
无论如何我都赢了
In which case, ha, I won.
要是我死了 那也全都是你的错
Or I'm dead and I'd like you to know that it's all your fault.
因为是你
It really is, you know.
激我这么干的 我做鬼也不放过你
You drove me to this. In which case, ha, I also won.
温柔一点
Sort of.
倒计时 三
I'm going in in three...
二
Two...
一
One.
啊
Hah!
纽顿 纽顿
Newton. Newton!
你在干什么
What have you done?
危险流浪者神经测试
Gipsy danger neural test...
将在20分钟后开始
commencing in 20 minutes.
危险流浪者神经测试将在20分钟后开始
Gipsy danger neural test commencing in 20 minutes.
嗯 我能进来吗
Mm. May I come in, mako?
所有机组成员到餐厅报到
All pilots report to mess hall.
很久很久以前 我曾给过你一个承诺
A long time ago, I made you a promise.
准备上场吧
(危险流浪者 "试运行" 8点)
这些信号传送器用不了了
These transmitters are non-operative.
得换掉
I need them replaced.
设置机甲测试模式
Setting harness for test mode.
等待副驾驶员加入
Waiting for second pilot.
两位驾驶员进舱
Two pilots onboard.
如果你不介意的话 我想站这边
I'm gonna take this side if you don't mind.
我的左臂曾经受过伤
My left arm's kinda shot.
没问题
Sure.
你是想问我点什么
Are you gonna say anything?
没必要了
No point.
五分钟后你会进入我大脑
In five minutes you're gonna be inside my head.
衣服很适合你
You look good.
驾驶员已就位 准备连线
Pilots onboard and ready to connect.
准备神经元对接
Prepare for neural handshake.
开始神经元对接
Initiating neural handshake.
好了 我们现在不是在模拟器上 麻子
We're not in the simulator now, mako.
一定记住 千万不要追赶兔子
Remember, don't chase the rabbit.
兔子就是随机读取脑神经元触发物的缩写
Random access brain impulse triggers.
记忆
Memories.
就让它们随意倾泻 别阻碍它们
Just let 'em flow, don't latch on.
要忽略它们 保持通感状态
Tune 'em out. Stay in the drift.
通感是无声的
The drift is silence.
神经元接口开始通感
Neural interface drift initiated.
看 罗利 那边
Look, Raleigh! Over there!
妈妈
Mama!
罗利 听我说 罗利 听我说
Raleigh, listen to me! Raleigh, listen to me!
大脑右半球已校准
Right hemisphere calibrated.
大脑左半球已校准
Left hemisphere calibrated.
准备激活机甲战士
Ready to activate the jaeger.
好吧 流浪者 校准得还不错
Okay, gipsy. Lining up nicely.
最好现在就准备
Better get ready.
驾驶员与机甲战士完成连接
Pilot to jaeger connection complete.
将军 将军
Marshal! Marshal!
我有话要跟你说
I need to talk to you.
现在不行 戈特利布先生
Not now, Mr. gottlieb.
你应该明白此刻
I'm sure you can appreciate...
对我来说意义重大
how important this moment is to me.
纽顿用废物创建出了神经桥梁
Newton created a neural bridge...
实现了与怪兽通感
from garbage and drifted with a kaiju.
我发现他的时候 他瘫倒在那里 看起来晕了过去
I found him prone, and he's sort of dazed.
我不知道 我不知道该怎么办
I don't exactly know what to do.
我告诉过你能成
I told you it would work.
是的 你做到了 你看到了什么
Yes, you did. Well, what'd you see?
只是一点头脑的碎片
You know, it was only a fragment of a brain,
其实我能看到的
so really all I was able to get was, like, a series...
只是一连串的图像或者感觉
of, uh, images or... or impressions. You know?
就像你一次又一次不停眨眼时
Like when you blink your eyes over and over and over again...
看到的东西一帧一帧的
all you really see are, like, frames.
静止图像 那就像是…
Um, it was emotional in the...
纽顿 好了 纽顿
Newton, Newton. Okay, Newton.
- 那是… - 纽顿看着我
- It was so... - Newton, look at me.
现在慢慢地 要详细地告诉我
Now I want you to take your time and be very specific.
好的
Okay.
我不认为
Well, I don't feel like...
它们只是单纯地受兽性驱使
they're just following some sort of animalistic urge,
不只是狩猎和采集
you know, just hunting and gathering.
我觉得它们是奉命攻击我们
And I think they're attacking us under orders.
这是不可能的
That's impossible.
- 怎么不可能 - 这绝对不可能
- Is that impossible? - It's impossible.
- 这不可能 你是在乱猜测 - 你为什么不跟怪兽通感试试
- Because... you know what? - Why don't you drift with a kaiju? !
你 闭上嘴
You! Shut up!
是 长官
Yes, sir.
你 接着说
You, keep talking.
这些怪兽 它们的主人 是殖民者
These beings, these masters, they're colonists.
他们掌握这个世界
They overtake worlds. They just...
等消耗尽一切后
they just consume them and then...
接着寻找下一个目标
then, they move on to the next.
他们以前来过这里 抱着试试看的想法
And they've been here before in sort of a trial run.
那是在恐龙时代
It was the dinosaurs.
但那时的空气并不适合他们生存
But the atmosphere wasn't conducive, right?
所以他们回去了
So they waited it out. And they waited it out.
现在臭氧枯竭
And now, you know, with ozone depletion,
一氧化碳升高 水被污染
and carbon monoxide, polluted waters...
简直就是为它们准备了大餐
well, we've practically terraformed it for them.
所以它们回来了 他们喜欢这环境
'Cause now they're coming back, and it's perfect.
第一波只是兽猎犬
See, the first wave, that was just the hounds.
一代到四代都不算什么
Categories 1 through 4, it was nothing.
它们的目的就是进攻人口最稠密的区域
Their sole purpose was to aim for the populated areas...
消灭我们
and take out the vermin us!
第二波才是灭杀者
The second wave, that is the exterminators.
把我们彻底收拾干净
And they will finish the job.
然后 地球的新房客进驻
And then, the new tenants will take possession.
这就是 两只不同的怪兽身上提取的DNA
See, the reason that I found the identical DNA...
是一模一样的 因为它们是克隆出来的
in the two separate kaiju organs is because they are grown!
纽顿 我需要你再做一次
Newton, I need you to do it again.
我需要更多的信息
I need more information.
我没法再做一次了
Why? I can't... I can'tdo it again.
我是说 除非你能找到
I...I mean, not unless you have...
一个活着的怪兽大脑
a fresh kaiju brain lying around.
你能吗
Do you?
真是太绝了
Pretty impressive.
他总算还记得怎么开动它
Yeah, he remembers how to turn it on.
嗨 放尊重点儿
Oi, show some respect.
他哥哥死了以后
When his brother died,
他独自带着机甲回到基地
he got the jaeger back to shore on his own.
在他之前我只见过一个人能做到这些
I've known one other pilot's been able to do that.
你应该知道有些人的生意
Now, there are certain individuals...
是专门保留和开发
whose business is the preservation...
各种怪兽的残骸
and exploitation of kaiju remains.
噢 对 没错 应该是黑市交易 对吗
Yeah, right, black market dealers, right?
他们几个小时就能搞定一笔买卖
Yep. They're in and out in a matter of hours.
他们中和血液中的酸性毒物
They neutralize the acidic factor of the blood,
换取他们想要的
and they harvest what they need.
这个人叫汉尼拔·周
Now, this guy, this is Hannibal chau.
他在亚洲专做怪兽的黑市交易
He runs the kaiju black market here in Asia.
我们资金紧缺的时候
When our funding ran out,
曾找过他帮忙 作为回报
we turned to him for help, and in return,
我给他各地区的怪兽残骸回收专有权
I gave him exclusive rights to all kaiju remains in the region.
你干过这事
You did that?
战争进入尾声了 先生们
Last days of war, gentlemen.
在芳路和图街交口
Go to the corner of fong and tull.
给他们这个名片 寻找这个标志
Show them that card. Look for that symbol.
但你要谨记 千万不能信任他
And a word to the wise, do not trust him.
连接校准完成
Calibration complete.
外壳 外壳被刺穿了
The hull! It went through the hull!
罗利 听我说 你需要…
Raleigh, listen to me! You need...
驾驶员连接失准
Pilot out of alignment.
两人都失准了
Both out of alignment.
都失准
Both of them?
都失准 流浪者 流浪者
Both of them. Gipsy, gipsy!
你们失准了
You're out of alignment!
你们两个都失准了
You are both out of alignment.
我没事 我能控制住它
I'm okay. Just let me control it.
两名驾驶员 连接失准
Pilot two, out of alignment.
你稳定下来了 但麻子小姐完全失准了
You're stabilizing. But mako is way out.
麻子 她开始追赶兔子了
Mako. She's starting to chase the rabbit!
麻子 别被记忆困住
Mako, don't get stuck in a memory.
和我在一起 回到现实中
Stay with me. Stay in the now.
别进入任何一段记忆中去
Don't engage in a memory.
麻子
Mako.
Mako!
听我说话
Listen to me.
麻子
Mako?
妈妈
Mama!
麻子
Mako.
这只是一段记忆
This is just a memory.
这不是现实
None of this is real.
武器系统启动
Weapons system engaged.
等离子榴弹炮充电中
Plasma Cannon powering up.
噢 不
Oh, no.
武器系统启动了 打开防备装置
Weapon system engaged! Go to fail-safe!
自动装置没反应
Fail-safe not responding.
神经封阻系统故障
There's a problem with the neural blocker!
麻子的记忆通感太强了
Her connection's way too strong!
- 充电完成 - 麻子
- Fully charged. - Mako!
麻子 快听我说
Mako, listen to me.
这只是一段记忆 这不是现实
This is just a memory. None of it is real.
所有人都撤离 快点
电源线 电源线
The power line! The power line!
快拔掉电源线
Get the main power line!
快拔掉电源线 让他们离线
Take them offline! Take them offline!
已经拔掉了
I just did.
武器系统取消
Weapon system disengaged.
麻子
Mako!
神经元连接训练取消
Neural bridge exercise invalid.
没事了 没事了
It's okay. It's okay.
通感关联终止
Drift sequence terminated.
是否需要再试一次
Would you like to try again?
(香港 贫民区)
在这儿
Hello.
嘘
Pss-psst.
你是不是想买怪兽骨粉
You looking for some kaiju bone powder?
骨粉
Some bone?
怪兽骨粉
Some bone powder?
不 我要那些干嘛
Uh, no, why would I want that?
壮阳 效果奇佳 我自己都用
Male potency. I take it myself.
噢 明白了 不过 谢谢你
I see. Uh, no, thank you.
我要找汉尼拔·周
I'm looking for Hannibal chau.
来吧
Come.
找汉尼拔·周
Hannibal chau, huh?
祝你好运
Good luck.
噢 我的天呐
Oh, my God!
我的天 这地方简直就是天堂
Oh, my God, this place is heaven!
那是第二代怪兽的淋巴结
That's a lymph gland from a category 2!
你这是在干嘛
And what are you working on here?
是角质层吗 崭新的吗
Is this a cuticle? In mint condition?
那是怪兽寄生虫吗
Is that a kaiju skin parasite?
我以前从没见过活的
I've never seen them alive before!
怪兽倒下 它们就会跟着死去
They-they usually die as soon as the kaiju falls!
我以为不可能养得活它们
I thought you couldn't keep them alive!
可以 泡在氨水里就行
You can if you soak 'em in ammonia.
你来干什么
What do you want?
我找汉尼拔·周
I'm looking for Hannibal chau.
有人告诉我他在这儿
I was told he was here.
你是什么人
Who wants to know?
我真的不能说
I really can't say.
啊 啊
Aah! Aah!
斯达克·潘特考斯特将军让我来的
Stacker pentecost sent me!
啊 啊
Aah! Aah!
太爽了 真是爽到家了
Oh, that's great. That's real great.
我想你就是汉尼拔·周 对吗
So I take it you're Hannibal chau, right?
喜欢这名字
You like the name?
它取自于
I took it from, uh...
我最喜欢的历史人物
My favorite historical character...
和我第二喜欢的布鲁克林川菜馆的名字
and my second-favorite szechuan restaurant in Brooklyn.
老实交代 你想干嘛
Now tell me what you want,
否则我把你当猪宰了喂怪兽身上的虱子
before I gut you like a pig and feed you to the skin louse.
麻子控制不了她的情感
She can't control her drift,
那个罗利又先失准
and he went out of phase first!
我们都知道发生了什么
We all know what happened.
我们不能姑息错误 怪兽在不断升级
We can't afford mistakes, the kaiju keep evolving,
我们已经被打得屁滚尿流了
they keep kicking our asses!
那小子过气了 麻子就是个菜鸟
He's a has-been, she's a rookie.
我不能让这样的人掩护我运输炸弹 长官
I don't want them protecting my bomb run, sir.
注意你的语气 查克先生
You need to watch your tone, Mr. Hansen.
嗨 待在那儿
Hey, stay there.
等我一会儿
Give me a moment.
你们俩丢人丢到家了
You two are a goddamn disgrace.
听着罗利 你会让我们所有的人丧命的
You're gonna get us all killed,
还会毁了这里的一切
and here's the thing, Raleigh:
我想执行完任务活着回来 因为我十分热爱我的生活
I want to come back from this mission 'cause I quite like my life.
不如你就这样 帮大家一个忙 消失
So why don't you just do us all a favor and disappear?
你最擅长干这个了
It's the only thing you're good at.
你给我闭嘴
Stop! Now!
是 没错
Yeah, that's right.
你最好管好你的小女朋友
You just hold back your little girlfriend.
别让她跑出来乱咬人
One of you bitches needs a leash.
- 向她道歉 - 去你的
- Apologize to her. - Screw you.
啊
Aah!
我说了 快点儿向她道歉
I saidapologize to her.
住手 够了
Hey! Hey! Enough!
你们干什么
What's going on?
你们俩起来
On your feet, both of you!
贝克特 麻子 到我办公室来
Becket, mori, into my office, now.
- 我跟你没完 - 你还没闹够
- No, we aren't finished! - Hey! Hey! This is over!
你是个特种兵 看在老天的份上
You're a ranger, for chrissake.
能不能有点素质
Why don't you start acting like one?
是我先失的准 这一切都是我的错
I went out of phase first. It was my mistake.
不
No.
是我的错
It was my mistake.
我就不应该安排你们俩做搭档
I should have never let you two in the same machine.
什么意思
So, what?
要雪藏我们
You're grounding us?
不是你
Not you.
我提请退出任务 将军
Permission to be dismissed, sir.
请求批准 麻子小姐
Permission granted, miss mori.
麻子
Mako.
长官 为什么要这样
Sir, what are you doing?
她是眼下最佳的副驾驶人选
She is the strongest candidate by far.
我们还有别的选择吗
What other options do we have?
告诉我
Huh? Tell me!
我希望你不要再挑战我的忍耐底线了 我的士兵
Do not let my calm demeanor fool you, ranger!
现在不服从上级 对你真的没有什么好处
Now is not a good moment for your insubordination!
麻子缺乏经验
Mako is too inexperienced...
在作战中无法控制好自己的记忆
to rein in her memories during combat.
这不是你雪藏她的理由 长官
That's not why you grounded her.
我进入过她的记忆 我都看见了
I was in her memories. I saw everything.
我才不管你自以为是的猜测
I don't care what you think you saw.
我知道她对你的意义
I know what she means to you.
我看见了
I saw it! I...
嗨 嗨
hey! Hey!
这次谈话到此结束
This conversation is over.
将军
Marshal.
将军 能不能停下 请你和我再聊两句
Marshal, can we just talk about this for one second? !
你不但救了她
You rescued her.
还养育了她
You raised her.
你现在不是在保护她
You're not protecting her now.
你是在压制她的能力
You are holding her back.
第一 以后千万别再碰我
One: Don't you ever touch me again.
第二 还是以后千万别再碰我
Two: Don't you ever touch me again.
我告诉你 你根本不知道我是谁
Now, you have no idea who the hell I am...
也根本不知道我的来历
or where I've come from,
我也绝对不会告诉你我的人生故事
and I'm not about to tell you my whole life story.
但是有一点可以告诉你 对于你和这里的每一个人
All I need to be to you and everybody in this dome...
我是你们的上级
is a fixed point.
会一直战斗到最后的人
The last man standing.
我不需要你的同情或者欣赏
I do not need your sympathy or your admiration.
我要的是你的服从和作战技能
All I need is your compliance and your fighting skills.
如果你给不了我这些
And if I can't get that,
就回到那个我找到你时
then you can go back to the wall...
你正在砌墙的地方
that I found you crawling on.
我说的够清楚了吧
Do I make myself clear?
是 长官
Yes, sir.
很好
Good.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我本应该提醒你
I should've warned you.
第一次通感会很惨烈
First drifts are rough.
因为你不仅仅是要进入我的回忆里
But you weren't just tapping into my memories.
你也会进入我哥哥的回忆里
You were tapping into my brother's too.
我哥哥被怪兽抓走的时候 我们还连接在一起
When yancy was taken, we were still connected.
我感受到他的害怕 他的痛苦
I felt his fear, his pain,
和无助 然后他就
his helplessness, and then...
死去了
He was gone.
我感受到了 我知道
I felt it. I know.
长久以来待在一个人的记忆里
You know, you live in someone else's head for so long...
很难适应这段记忆突然变得沉默
the hardest part to deal with is the silence.
不过 让另一个人真正进入你的记忆
To let someone else in, to really connect,
需要足够的信任
you have to trust them.
今天咱俩通感信号很强
And today the drift was strong.
它的心脏
Her heart.
你上一次看见是什么时候
When's the last time you saw it?
很久以前了
Not in a long time.
往下拉 向左移动一点
Movement in the breach.
双重事件
Double event.
两个信号
Two signatures.
详细描述 第四代
Dilation indicator, category 4.
不好意思
Excuse me.
缺口在23点时被侵入
The breach was exposed at 2300 hours.
我们收到两个信号 都是第四代
We have two signatures, both category 4s.
它们的代号是大立和棱皮龟
Code names: Otachi and leatherback.
一小时内就会到到达香港
They'll reach Hong Kong within the hour.
疏散全城市民 关闭大桥
Evacuate the city. Shut down the Bridges.
每一个市民现在都必须马上去避难所
I want every single civilian in a refuge right now.
红色暴风 切尔诺贝利阿尔法
Crimson typhoon, cherno Alpha,
我需要你们去保卫海港
I want you to frontline the harbor.
守住大陆架
Stay on the miracle mile.
突袭者 你留后防守
Striker, I want you to stay back,
保护海岸线
look after the coastline.
我们绝不能失去你们
We cannot afford to lose you,
不到万不得已不要出击
so only engage as a final option.
是 长官
Yes, sir!
你们两个
You two.
原地待命
You stay put.
开始行动
Let's go!
劳森特中心 突袭者开始行动
Loccent, striker's got the ball and we're on the roll.
中心 即将就位 等待命令
Loccent...Near positions and awaiting your orders.
待在一英里大陆架 不要轻易动手
Remain in the miracle mile. Engage at your discretion.
听着 大家都提高警惕
Guys, keep your eyes open.
这第四代无论是体型还是重量
These category 4s are the biggest we've ever seen,
都是我们见过最大的
both in size and weight.
切尔诺阿尔法到达目标区域
Cherno Alpha reaching target zone.
准备脱离运输机
Disengaging transport.
切尔诺阿尔法已经就位
Cherno Alpha in position. Miracle mile.
切尔诺阿尔法掌控海岸线
Cherno Alpha holding the coastline.
灯塔开启
Beacon is on.
看看他们
Look at 'em.
他们相信怪兽是上天派来的
They believe the kaiju are sent from heaven.
上帝以此表达他对我们所做所为的不满
That the gods are expressing their displeasure with our behavior.
愚昧的人
The silly bastards.
你信仰什么
And what do you believe?
我
Well...
我信仰怪兽骨粉能卖到500美元一磅
I believe that kaiju bone powder is 500 bucks a pound.
你需要什么
What do you want?
我需要研究一个怪兽的大脑
I need to access a kaiju brain.
完好无损的大脑
Completely intact.
不不不
No, no, no.
它们的颅骨板很稠密
The skull plate is so dense...
等你钻进去之后
that by the time you drill into it...
大脑已经腐烂光了
the brain's rotted away.
我说的是次级大脑
But I'm talking about the secondary brain.
你我都知道怪兽的体积超大
Now we both know that the kaiju are so large...
它们需要两个大脑才能走路 跟恐龙一样
they need two brains to move around, like a dinosaur.
我就想弄到那个
I want to get my hands on that.
嗯
Mm.
你要个次级大脑干什么用
What the hell do you want a secondary brain for, anyway?
怪兽身上每个部分都能卖钱
I mean, every part of the kaiju sells.
软骨 脾脏 肝脏
Cartilage, spleen, liver.
甚至是粪便
Even the crap!
每立方米的粪便含有大量的磷
One cubic meter of crap...
可以用来给整片农田施肥
has enough phosphorous in it to fertilize a whole field!
但是大脑
But the brain...
全是氨水
Too much ammonia.
你要它干嘛 小兄弟
So what's the deal, little fella?
这是个机密
Well, that's classified.
我不能跟你说 打死都不能说
So I couldn't tell you. Even if I wanted to.
嗯
Mm.
但我的活儿还真挺酷的
But it is pretty cool.
跟你说说也没什么
So I might tell you.
我告诉你吧
I'm gonna tell you.
我找到办法和怪兽实现通感了
I figured out how to drift with a kaiju.
你在耍我 小子
Are you funnin' me, son?
搞清它们的头脑太有意思了
It's fascinating how their minds work.
每个独立的怪兽 它的头脑都被连接了
Every single kaiju, his mind's connected.
这个物种好像 好像是蜂群式思维
The species has like a... like a hive mind.
兔崽子
Holy Jesus.
你真的实现过了
You've gone and done it, haven't you?
就一小会儿而已
I did it a little bit, yeah.
你这个该死的白痴
You goddamn moron.
移动右边 三点钟
三点钟
雷云准备 出击
中心 暴风和阿尔法有麻烦
Loccent! Typhoon and Alpha are in trouble.
我们去解围
We're movin' in!
待在位置上 你们不准出击
You are to hold your ground. Do not engage.
我需要你们携带核弹
We need you to carry that bomb.
明白吗
Do you copy?
我们不能眼看着他们被打死 来吧
Jesus, we can't just sit here and watch 'em die. Come on!
顾不了这些了 中心 我们现在出击
Ah, screw this. Loccent, we're movin' in now!
红色暴风完了
我们来干掉这个混蛋
切尔诺阿尔法报告 我们被某种强酸击中了
Cherno Alpha, we've been hit with some type of acid!
来吧
Come on!
外壳彻底破损 我们需要支援
Hull has been compromised. We need backup immediately!
坚持住 我们马上过去支援
Just hold on, cherno! We're on our way!
水位已经到达反应堆
用尽全力
Our power move! Yeah!
和阿尔法失去联络 长官
We just lost cherno, sir.
启动地对空导弹
Engaging air missiles!
发生了什么事 怎么回事
What's going on? What happened?
冲击波 干扰了机甲战士的电路
The blast. It jumbled all the jaegers' electrical circuits.
那是什么鬼东西
What the hell was that?
中心 我以前从来没见过
Loccent! I've never seen that before.
中心 它们进化了
Loccent! They're adapting.
这不是防御机制 是武器
This isn't a defense mechanism, it's a weapon!
联络突袭者
Get me striker!
没反应 长官 五号机甲数字接口被毁
Nothing, sir. The mark 5's digital's fried.
我需要两个小时重置辅助系统
It'll take me two hours to reroute the auxiliary.
所有机甲都是数控的
All the jaegers, they're digital!
不都是 将军
Not all of them, marshal.
流浪者是模拟机 核控
Gipsy's analog. Nuclear.
两头怪兽袭击我们 我们得撤离 这边走
We got two kaijus. We gotta get out.
稍等一会儿 劳驾 发生什么事了
Hang on a second. Excuse me. Wh-what's going on?
有两头该死的怪兽
There are two goddamn kaiju...
直接冲着香港过来了
headed straight for Hong Kong city.
不 这不可能 以前从来没有两个一起来的
No, no, no. That's not possible. There's never been two before.
是吗 没准儿是因为
Well, maybe that's 'cause...
以前没人跟它们通感过 大天才
nobody ever drifted with one before, eh, genius? !
机甲驾驶员的通感 是双向的
When jaeger pilots drift, it's a two-way street.
- 通过桥接 对吧 - 是的
- A bridge, right? - Of course. Yes!
架起一种关联
It sets up a connection.
双向关联
Both ways!
蜂群式思维 是你说的
"A hive mentality," you said!
或许那些怪兽 它们是在寻找你
Maybe those kaiju are tryin' to find you.
那我们 我们怎么办
What... what're we gonna do?
我得去我自己的怪兽避难所躲过这一劫
I'm gonna wait out this shitstorm in my own private kaiju bunker.
但是你 得去公共避难所
But you are going to a public refuge.
我去过那儿一次
I tried it once. Once.
就一次
Once.
你给我滚出去
Now get the hell outta here.
对不起 让一让
Excuse me!
啊
Aah!
让开 我是医生 我是医生
Move! Move! I'm a doctor! I'm a doctor!
等等 让我进去
Okay, hold on. Let me in.
快走 让我进去 我是医生
Okay, I'm a doctor. Okay, let me in, I'm a doctor.
请您立即进入避难所避难
Please proceed immediately to your anti-kaiju refuge.
没有应急电力供应
There's no emergency power.
- 必须撤离 - 让我再想想别的法子
- We gotta bail. - I'm gonna try somethin' else.
不 别解除驾驶
No! Don't disengage!
我的胳膊
Aah! My arm!
起来 快站起来 老头子
Hey! Come on! Get on your feet, old man!
混蛋 别这么叫我
Don't call me that!
它就在外面 我们必须马上离开这里
He's right outside. We gotta get outta here now!
我们哪儿也不去
We're not goin' anywhere!
眼下只有你和我
Now you and I are the only thing...
挡在这个丑八怪和整个城市的
standin' between that ugly bastard...
千万条人命中间了
and a city of 2 million people.
现在我们要做出抉择 是坐在这里等
Now we have a choice here.
We either sit and wait...
还是用这些信号枪
or we take these flare guns...
孤注一掷地跟它拼了
and do something really stupid.
- 你的胳膊怎么样 - 把枪给我就是了
- How's your arm? - Ah, just give me the gun.
嗨 混蛋
Hey, you!
我想我们激怒它了
I think we just pissed it off!
好了吗 麻子 做好准备 这是实战
All right, mako. Get ready, this is for real!
好样的
Yeah!
上啊 流浪者 狠狠地打
Come on, gipsy! Kick his ass!
来吧 准备好了吗 一起来吧
Come on! Let's do this! Together!
天马流星拳
Elbow rocket!
出拳
Now!
啊
Aah!
坚持住 麻子
Hang on, mako!
等离子榴弹炮 发射
Plasma Cannon, now!
等离子榴弹炮准备
Plasma Cannon engaged.
全部打光
Empty the clip!
等一下
Wait.
我想那家伙应该是死了
I think this guy's dead.
我们最好再检查一下
But let's check for a pulse.
好的
Okay.
检查完毕
No pulse.
它在上面停下来了
He stopped right above us.
我的天呐
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
这里不是避难所 这里是餐厅
This isn't a refuge. This is... this is a buffet line!
它知道我在这儿
He knows I'm here.
He knows I'm here!
它知道我们都在这儿
He knows we're all here!
你不明白 它要抓我
No, you don't understand, he's trying to get me!
它一定知道我在这儿 它要抓我
He knows I'm here and he's trying to get me!
它 它是要他的
什么意思 你说什么
What was that? What did you say? !
怪兽要来了
让我出去 让我出去
I gotta get out of here! Let me out of here!
我要… 啊 我操
I got... Ah, come on!
我的眼镜
Those were expensive glasses.
真是糟透了
This is the worst.
转矩准备完毕
Torque engaged.
无法精确定位 它动作太快
I can't pinpoint it. It's movin' quick.
一定要提高警惕
Keep your eyes open.
直升机 你能传给我图像吗
Choppers, do you have a visual? Over.
来吧
Come on!
我来制住它
I'll hold it!
打开左翼冷却剂
Vent the coolant on the left flank!
冷却剂打开
Coolant venting.
已经打开了
Venting coolant.
上升过程氧气流失中
Atmosphere loss in progress.
温度下降 我们的氧气不够了
Temperature's droppin'! We're losing oxygen!
两枚等离子榴弹炮已发射
Both plasma cannons are shot.
我们无计可施了 麻子
We're out of options, mako.
不 还有一个办法
准备亮剑
Sword deployment.
为了我的家人
海拔驱动装置 失去平衡
Altitude actuation off-balance.
距离地面还有5万英尺
50, 000 feet to ground contact.
看 在那儿
Look, there!
海拔驱动装置 失去平衡
Altitude loss critical.
4万英尺
40, 000 feet.
流浪者 听我命令
Gipsy, listen to me!
松开所有减震器
Loosen all the shock absorbers,
用陀螺仪平衡身体 蜷缩抱团
use your gyroscope as balance and ball up!
这是唯一的机会
It's your only chance!
2万英尺
20, 000 feet.
丢掉燃料
Fuel purge!
快
Now!
撞击警告
Impact alert.
我们下降速度太快了
We're comin' in too fast.
速度太快 准备好 麻子
We're comin' in too fast. Brace for impact, ma...
麻子 说句话
Mako, talk to me.
麻子 你没事吧
Mako, you okay?
没事
Yeah.
你呢
You?
- 马上去找葛斯勒博士 - 是 长官
- Go to Dr. geiszler now! - Yes, sir!
我需要剩下的两个机甲战士全面恢复各项功能
I want the two remaining jaegers back to 100% functionality.
是 长官
Yes, sir!
我们要得到皮肤 爪子和翅膀
We're gonna harvest the skin, the talons and the wing.
德国人看到一定会乐疯了
Germans are gonna go nuts for that stuff.
我们来看看地图
Let me see that map.
这里是怪兽倒下的地方
Here is where the kaiju fell,
我们就集中精力在这里动手
here's where we concentrate our efforts.
- 我去搞定 老大 - 好的
- We'll get it, boss. - Right.
嗨
Hey!
看看谁回来了 你这个白痴独眼龙
Okay, guess who's back, you one-eyed bitch?
你欠我一个怪兽大脑
And you owe me a kaiju brain.
罗利
Raleigh!
我那臭小子不会认输
My kid'd never admit it...
但他很感激你
But he's grateful.
我们俩都是
We both are.
贝克特先生
Mr. becket!
麻子小姐
Miss mori!
在我毕生的戎马生涯里
In all of my years fighting...
从没见过 了不起
I've never seen anything like that.
干得漂亮
Well done.
我为你骄傲
Proud of you.
为所有人骄傲
Proud of us all.
不过
But...
别怪我不近人情 我们还没有时间庆祝胜利
As harsh as it sounds, there is no time to celebrate.
我们失去了两组队友
We lost two crews.
我们没时间难过
No time to grieve.
重置战事钟
Reset that clock.
Reset the clock.
我真不敢相信你居然利用我
I still can't believe what you did to me.
我差点被活吞
I mean, I coulda been eaten.
要的就是这个效果
Well, that was definitely the plan.
算你走运 就这么躲过去了
Lucky for you, that didn't become necessary, huh?
非常感谢 你真是个好人
Okay. Thank you so much. You're so kind.
我简直受宠若惊
I really appreciate all of this.
现在你能不能告诉我 为什么你的手下取个大脑
But now do you mind tellin' me exactly what is taking so long...
要花那么长时间
for your workers to get that brain?
因为他们 先得往里面灌二氧化碳
Well, they pump the cavity full of co2,
就像做腹腔镜手术那样
just like in any other laparoscopic surgery.
好吧 这倒是
Okay, yes, obviously,
那么 二氧化碳会延缓酸性反应
the co2's gonna delay the acidic reaction, yes.
没错 这样才能取材
And it allows us to harvest.
而且我手下的工作服里注满氧气
But our boys need oxygen pumped into their suits.
行动就会缓慢
They move slow.
那边怎么样了 伙计们
What's goin' on in there, boys?
我们已经到达
We've reached...
上骨盆地带了
The upper pelvic area.
正去往第25节椎骨
Moving to the 25th vertebra.
天呐
Shit.
正在穿越它的内脏 老大
Even through the suit, boss,
这儿闻起来一股臭猫烂鱼味儿
it smells like dead catfish in here.
老大
Boss.
次级大脑
The secondary brain...
- 损坏了 - 噢
- Is damage. - Oh.
没用了 已经毁了
It's ruin. Destroy.
真是见鬼 这些办事不力的家伙
Bitch! How could they screw that up? !
等等 等等
Wait. Wait.
什么
What was that?
他说等等 等什么
Did he say "wait"? Why wait?
听到了吗
Do you hear that?
像是心跳声
It's like a heartbeat.
我的天呐
Oh, my God.
不会吧 等等
Oh, my God, this can't be. Hold on a second.
把对讲机给我
Hey! Let me have that!
别吵 别吵
Shh, shh! Listen, listen!
听听这个
Listen to this.
它怀孕了
It's pregnant.
别别别
No, no!
求你了
Please.
不 不
No! No.
我就知道
I knew it.
啊
Aah!
死了
Gone.
它的肺还没发育完全
His lungs weren't fully formed.
脐带缠住了它的脖子
Umbilical cord tied around his neck.
在子宫外它连一分钟也活不了
No way he could survive outside the womb for more than a minute.
我一只眼 而且只看一眼
One look, that's all I needed.
就知道它活不了
I knew he wouldn't make it.
丑八怪
Ugly little bastard.
无论如何 我都…
Anyway, I woulda...
你的病有多严重
How sick are you?
为什么不早告诉我
And why didn't you tell me?
告诉你什么
What's to tell?
要知道那些一代机甲
You know, them mark 1s,
我们仅仅花了14个月 就把那些臭小子制造出来
we scraped them bad boys together in 14 months.
那会儿我们根本就没有考虑过屏蔽辐射的措施
Last thing we were thinking about was radiation shielding.
我身上扛着十几项任务
I ran nearly a dozen missions.
医学雷达却从没检测出我有问题
I stayed under the medical radar for awhile...
直到我最后一次在东京驾驶
but the last time I jockeyed was Tokyo.
当时我独自战斗了三个小时
I finished the fight solo, but for three hours...
我有了反应
I burned.
他们警告过我 如果再进入机甲参加战斗
They warned me if I ever stepped foot into a jaeger again,
将会付出巨大代价
the toll would be too much.
你和我是唯一两个能单独操作机甲的人
You and I are the only two that ever ran solo combat.
所以我找你回来
That's why I brought you here.
- 什么事 - 果然发生了
- What is it? - Sir, it's happening.
我刚收到两条信号
I just got two signatures...
空前强烈 足有40米高
with unprecedented dilation, 40-meter spikes.
第几代的
What category?
正在核对比率 是第四代
Checking the ratios, category four.
它们的方向
Where're they headed?
问题就在这儿 它们没有设定任何方向
That's the thing, they're not headin' anywhere.
在缺口上方盘旋
They're hovering just above the breach.
看起来像在保护什么东西
It's...it's like they're protecting it or something.
通知流浪者 突袭者 准备出发
All right, gipsy, striker, on deck.
长官 赫克无法驾驶 他的手臂
Sir, herc cannot ride. His arm...
执行命令
You heard me.
两条信号
Two signatures.
两条
Two? ! There are...
你说缺口处有两条怪兽信号
there are two kaiju signatures in the breach,
不是我之前猜测的三条吗
not three like I predicted? !
赫尔曼 我今天心情非常不好 明白吗
Hermann! I haven't exactly had a very good day, okay? !
我只有5分钟时间
I got about 5 minutes...
应该是三个
Should be three kaijus.
不然怪兽大脑就死了
Before brain death occurs here!
我不想浪费时间讨论你的理论
I don't wanna spend it talking about your theories!
情况不对
This is all wrong!
应该有三只怪兽过来 绝不止两只
There should be three kaijus coming through, not two!
应该三只却来了两只
There should be three and there's two?
抱歉 犯错误是痛苦的事
I'm sorry, it hurts to be wrong, doesn't it, hermann?
我没犯错 只是有些东西没搞清楚
I am not wrong, but there is something here that we don't understand.
你在预测模型里犯下的种种错误
Okay. Hermann, hopefully we can argue about any mistakes...
我们会探讨
you made in your predictive model in the future!
但此时此刻
But in the meantime,
神经接口值超出了正常范围
the neural interface is way off the charts!
如果想帮忙 就别废话
If you want to help, help with that!
纽顿 我绝对不会错
Newton, I am not wrong.
只有一种办法能确定
There is only one way to make sure...
那就是我们
And that is to do this...
一起干
Together.
我跟你一起做
I'll go with you.
机甲战士驾驶员不是两个吗
That's what the jaeger pilots do,
分担神经性负荷
share the neural load.
你说真的 真愿意为我这么做
You're serious? You...you would do that for me?
你说真愿意跟我试试
Or you would do that with me?
地球已经到了最危急的时刻 只要有办法
Well, with worldwide destruction a certain alternative...
我就没有别的选择
Do I really have a choice?
我们一起来发誓 我们来主宰这个坏小子
Then say it with me, my man: "We're gonna own this bad boy!"
苍天在上 我们誓将搞清一切 主宰一切
By jove, we are going to own this thing for sure!
天童 天童
Oi, tendo. Tendo!
你还没穿好装备
You're not suited up.
我知道 我知道
Yeah, I'm aware of that, Elvis.
我需要知道发生了什么
I need to know what's going on.
让你穿好 你就穿好
He said suit up, so suit up.
我总不能一个人驾驶突袭者吧 对不对
Tendo, I can't pilot striker on my own, now, can I? !
老爸受伤了 谁来做我的副驾驶
Dad's hurt, so who's gonna be my copilot?
以前没感觉这么紧
I don't remember it being so tight.
回到机甲体内作战会要了你的命
Getting back into that jaeger will kill you.
不回去所有人都会没命
Not gettin' into one would kill us all.
听着 你是个勇敢的女孩
Listen, you are a brave girl.
能看着你长大那是我的幸运
I'm so lucky to have seen you grow.
现在我决定我这么做
But if I'm going to do this...
我还需要你保护我呢
I need you to protect me.
能做到吗
Can you do that?
好了
Hey.
所有人 听好了
Everyone, listen up!
今天
Today...
我们的最后希望
At the edge of our hope...
我们的最后一刻生命
At the end of our time...
我们不仅仅选择了相信自己
We have chosen not only to believe in ourselves,
还选择了相信彼此
but in each other.
今天站在这里的不论是男人还是女人
Today there's not a man nor woman in here...
都不是孤军奋战
that shall stand alone.
就在今天
Not today.
今天我们将直面入侵我们家园的魔鬼
Today we face the monsters that are at our door...
将和它们决一死战
and bring the fight to them!
今天我们要推翻启示录的末日预言
Today we are canceling the apocalypse!
马上进入安全区域
Go to the safety zone right now.
将军
Hey, marshal!
刚才你讲得真好
You know, that was a great speech,
但是 我想知道
but how exactly are you and I...
你和我怎么实现通感
supposed to match up in there?
通感时我会心无旁骛
I carry nothing into the drift.
没有回忆 没有恐惧 没有军阶
No memories, no fear. No rank.
至于你
And as for you...
再简单不过了
Well, you're easy.
你傲慢任性 还跟你老爸有矛盾
You're an egotistical jerk with daddy issues.
第一天见到你 我就看透你了
A simple puzzle I solved on day one.
但你毕竟有你老爸的血统
But you are your father's son...
我们的通感应该很好
So we'll drift just fine.
我明白了
Works for me.
嗨 儿子
Hey, now.
当你跟人通感了以后
When you drift with someone,
可能会觉得没必要再交谈了
you feel like there's nothing to talk about.
我只是不想憋着话
I just don't want to regret...
等着今后没法说再后悔
all the things that I never said out loud.
不要
Don't.
你不用说出来 不用说
You don't need to.
我都知道
I know them all.
一直都知道
I always have.
嗨 帅哥
Hey. Hey, handsome.
我会想你的
Oh, I'm gonna miss you.
替我好好照顾它
You look after him for me.
将军
Stacker.
跟你并肩作战的可是
That's my son you got there.
我的儿子
My son.
知道吗 麻子 这些年我一直活在过去的阴影里
You know, mako, all those years I spent livin' in the past,
从来没有想过人生和未来
I never really thought about the future.
但是此刻
Until now.
是我人生中最好的时光
I never did have very good timing.
准备好了吗
You ready for this?
是的
Oh, yes, yes.
神经元连线启动 倒数5秒
Initiating neural handshake in 5...
4 3 2 1
4, 3, 2, 1.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
是的 没事
Yes, of course.
我完全没有问题
I'm completely fine.
通感 你看见了吗
The drift. You saw it?
- 是的 - 是吗
- Yeah. - Did you?
听着 我们得警告他们
Listen, we have to warn them.
机甲战士 缺口 还有计划
The jaegers... the breach... the plan...
那计划不可行
it's not going to work.
运输脱离
Disengaging transport.
中心 所有端口封闭
Loccent, all ports sealed.
准备下潜
Ready to submerge.
所有端口封闭 准备下潜
All ports sealed. Ready to submerge.
双方神经元连接吻合率100%
Man: Both neural handshakes at 100%.
神经元连接确认 长官
Neural handshake confirmed, sir.
关岛海域附近 两头怪兽仍处于环形阵势
Two actives still in circle formation in the Guam quadrant.
它们的代号是恶灵 雷兽
Code names: Scunner, raiju.
- 都是四代怪兽 - 收到
- Both category 4. - Roger that.
离海崖还有半英里 准备跳
Half a mile to the ocean cliff, we jump!
缺口还有3公里
It's 3, 000 meters to the breach.
半英里 可我连前方半英寸都看不见
Half a mile? ! I can't even see a damn inch ahead!
我们要怎么扔下这枚核弹
How are we supposed to deliver the bomb?
能见度为零
Visibility's zero.
现在转为自动导航
Switching to instruments now.
长官
Sir!
流浪者 你的右侧有动静 三点方向
Gipsy, you have movement on your right. Three o'clock!
三点方向
Three o'clock!
半径100英尺 安全
100 feet radius, clear.
右翼安全 没有敌情
Right flank's clear. I got nothing.
是左翼 速度飞快
Left now! And movin' fast!
打破了怪兽的最快纪录
Fastest kaiju on record!
我什么都看不见 它移动得太快了
I don't see anything. It's movin' too fast!
盯紧敌人 流浪者 还有600米就到缺口了
Eyes on the prize, gipsy. 600 meters from the drop.
400米 越来越近了
400 meters and closing.
怪兽停下了
Bogeys are stopping.
突袭者 怪兽停下来了
Striker! Bogeys are stopping.
一点钟方向
One o'clock.
将军 你要干什么
Marshal, what are you doing? !
它们停下来了
They're stopping.
为什么停下来了
Why the hell are they stopping? !
我才不管呢 将军 我们离下落点只有300米了
I don't give a damn, sir! We're 300 meters from the jump!
肯定有问题 突袭者 怪兽没有跟上来
Something's not right! Herc: Striker, the bogeys aren't following.
现在可以跳下
Take the leap now!
千万别 计划不可行
Don't do it! Don't do it, it's not gonna work!
闪开 白痴
Move, you fascist!
炸掉缺口的计划不可行
Blowing up the breach, it's not gonna work!
你什么意思 为什么不可行
What do you mean? What's not gonna work?
缺口张开并不意味着
Sir, just because the breach is open...
你的核弹能顺利穿过
does not mean you're gonna be able to get a bomb through.
缺口原本就能读取怪兽
The breach genetically reads the kaiju...
好比超市里的收款根据货品条码完成 这样才能顺利完成
like a barcode at the supermarket and then lets them pass.
所以 你得设法让缺口误以为
Okay, so you're gonna have to fool the breach...
你跟怪兽有一样的条形码
into thinking that you have the same code!
我们怎么才能做到
And how are we supposed to do that?
得让它认为你也是一头怪兽
By making it think you are a kaiju.
你必须攀附在怪兽身上驶入缺口
You have to lock onto the kaiju, ride it into the breach.
T缺口就会将你
He throat will then read...
读取为怪兽 让你通过
the kaiju's genetic code and let you pass.
如果你不这么做 核弹会跟以往一样射偏
If you don't do it, the bomb will deflect off the breach...
任务就失败了
like it always has and the mission will fail.
行了 现在你听了这么多了
All right, now that you've heard all that,
想办法跳吧
striker, take the leap!
长官 收到从缺口发出的第三个信号
Sir! I have a third signature emerging from the breach!
第三个信号从缺口发出
Third signature emerging from the breach.
三重攻势
It's a triple event.
天呐 我是对的
Oh, God, I was right.
那东西有多大 是第几代
How big is it? What category?
是第五代
Category 5.
突袭者
Striker,
是第五代怪兽
it's a category 5.
是第一只
The first ever.
突袭者 我们看到它了
Striker, we see him.
我们就在你后方100米处
We're right behind you, about 100 meters.
我们会包抄你的三点方向
We're gonna come around your three o'clock,
从侧面进攻
try to flank him.
标准两队阵型
Standard two-team formation.
你先控制它一会儿…
Just keep him busy for a few mi...
抵御冲击
brace for impact!
准备亮剑
Chain sword deployed.
去死吧 你这混蛋
Let's get this son of a bitch!
流浪者 你12点方向有敌人
Gipsy, comin' up on your 12 o'clock!
全速来袭
Full speed!
快点躲避
Get out of the way!
投弹装置卡住了
The release is jammed!
我们无法投弹 将军
We can't deliver the payload, sir!
我们的武器还在
We're still armed.
但机甲外壳受损
But the hull is compromised!
一半的系统停滞 将军
Half our systems are offline, sir.
我们需要重新…
We need to override the...
啊
Aah!
两只怪兽向突袭者快速逼近
Both kaijus converging on striker fast!
挺住啊 突袭者 我们来支援你
Hang on, striker! We're comin' to ya!
不 流浪者 不要过来支援我们
No! Gipsy! Do not come to our aid!
- 听到没有 - 坚持
- Do you copy? - Hang on!
离我们越远越好
Stay as far back as you can!
我们可以帮到你 我们朝你们过来了
We can still reach you. We're comin' for you.
不 罗利 听我说
No, Raleigh, listen to me.
你很明白你该做什么
You know exactly what you have to do!
流浪者是核能的
Gipsy is nuclear!
把她带到缺口那儿去
Take her to the breach!
我听见了 长官
I hear you, sir.
朝缺口方向
Headin' for the breach.
结构损伤 前进80%
Structural damage, 80%. Now...
麻子 听着
Mako. Listen.
你能完成任务
You can finish this.
我永远都在你身边
I'll always be here for you.
你永远都会在通感里见到我
You can always find me in the drift.
我们是一个活动核反应堆
We're a walking nuclear reactor.
我们一定会炸毁缺口
We can destroy the breach.
下一步怎么做 将军
What can we do, sir?
我们做一回清道夫
We can clear a path!
给他们开路
For the lady!
他们是想要引爆核弹
They're gonna detonate the payload.
我老爸总说
Well, my father always said:
把握机会 永不言悔
He said if you have the shot, you take it!
让我们干吧
So let's do this!
我很荣幸 将军
It was a pleasure, sir.
再见 老师
Sensei.
我会想你的
Aishitemasu.
所有系统 陷入危机
All systems critical.
机体失去平衡
Fluid loss.
系统陷入危机了
Systems are critical!
燃料泄漏
Fuel is leaking!
我们的右腿受伤了
Our right leg's crippled!
红色警报
Code red.
- 我们拼了 - 所有系统 陷入危机
- Let's finish this. - All systems critical.
他们在干嘛
What are they doing?
完成最终的任务
Finishing the mission.
中心 我们获取了怪兽残骸
Loccent. We have the kaiju carcass.
我们正在向缺口行进
We're heading for the breach.
你们最好是对的
You guys better be right.
因为无论如何 我们都要完成这个任务
'Cause one way or another, we're gettin' this thing done.
听我倒数 启动喷射
On my count, rear jets!
三 二 一
Three, two, one.
开始
Now!
抱紧了
Hold on.
麻子小姐的氧气快用完了 不到一半了
Mako's oxygen is down. Half capacity!
能启动备用吗
Can you reroute it?
我正在试 长官
I'm tryin', sir.
- 坚持住 麻子 - 热能净化启动
- Hold on, mako. - Heat shaft purge.
我要烧死你这个大混蛋
I'm gonna burn this son of a bitch.
他们进去了
They're in.
成功了
They're in! It worked.
机甲左半侧 氧气含量低 危险级
Oxygen main, left hemisphere, critical levels.
15%功能可供运行
Operating at 15% capacity.
10%功能可供运行
10% capacity.
5%功能可供运行
5% capacity.
他把氧气给麻子小姐了
He's givin' her his oxygen.
机甲右半侧 氧气含量低
Right hemisphere oxygen...
没事了 麻子
It's okay now, mako.
危险级
Critical level.
我们做到了
We did it.
剩下的我一个人就可以完成
I can finish this alone.
顺势下坠就行了
All I have to do is fall.
这个谁都会
Anyone can fall.
罗利 你的氧气含量已经逼近危险值
Raleigh, your oxygen levels are critical now.
你没有多少时间了
You don't have much time.
开始进行堆芯熔化 马上弃船
Start the core meltdown and get out of there.
听到了吗
Do you hear me?
现在马上弃船
Get out of there now!
一号逃生舱已弹出 没有爆炸 长官
One pod is ejected. No detonation, sir.
中心 如果还能听见我
Loccent, if you can still hear me,
我现在开始反应堆破坏程序
I'm initiating reactor override now.
手动激活程序
Manual activation required.
- 发生什么了 - 触发器离线
- What's goin' on? ! - Trigger's offline!
他得手动完成
He has to do it by hand.
他没时间了
He's out of time.
得马上启动自毁程序
He has to self-destruct now.
手动激活程序 发生故障
Manual activation required.
不
No!
手动制动开启
Manual override initiated.
60秒后开始堆芯熔化
Core meltdown in t-minus 60.
55秒后反应堆熔化
Reactor meltdown in 55 seconds.
50秒
50 seconds.
逃生舱准备中
Evac pod engaged.
5 4 3 2 1
5, 4, 3, 2, 1.
反应堆燃料熔化开始
Reactor meltdown commence.
正中目标 缺口已经塌了
Direct hit! The breach has collapsed!
启动直升机
To the choppers!
马上启动直升机
To the choppers now!
看到一号逃生舱
Visuals on first pod.
跟踪信号强烈 生命迹象平稳
Tracking solid. Vital signs are good.
好极了 二号逃生舱呢
Okay, where's the second pod?
正在追踪 没有发现生命迹象
I'm tracking it, but I'm getting no vital signs.
我摸不到他的脉搏
I can't find his pulse.
他好像停止呼吸了
I don't think he's breathing.
能读到他的脉搏吗
Can you read his pulse?
- 有脉搏吗 - 罗利
- Does he have a pulse? - Raleigh?
- 罗利 - 没有
- Raleigh? - I don't know.
麻子小姐 听我说
Mako, listen to me.
可能是因为传感器出故障了
It could be the sensors are not working.
现在还不能确定
We can't be sure.
不
No.
不要 别死
No. Don't go.
麻子
Mako.
别离开我
No. Don't go.
麻子
Mako.
别死 求你了
Don't go. Please.
再这样我就被你勒死了
You're squeezing me too tight.
我快要窒息了
I couldn't breathe.
我是赫拉克勒斯·汉斯将军
This is marshal Hercules Hansen.
缺口被封死了
The breach is sealed.
战事钟永远归零
Stop the clock!
麻子小姐 罗利 我们获取到了你们的位置
Mako, Raleigh. We have your position.
直升机正在途中 稍等一会儿就到
The choppers are on their way. J-just hang on.
你们没事吧
Are you okay?
收到请回话
Do you copy?
伙计们
Uh, guys?
我那该死的鞋在哪儿
Where is my goddamn shoe?